A Guide to the Correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Housing Development Authority, 1973-1980
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Correspondence and subject files of the Director of the Virginia Housing Development Authority,, 1973-1980
The Library of Virginia
43911
4 cu. ft. (4 boxes)
Virginia Housing Development Authority
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from the Virginia Housing Development Authority, Richmond, Virginia, 6 Aug 2008.
Biographical Information
The Virginia Housing Development Authority (VHDA) is the state's mortgage finance agency. Created in 1972 by the Virginia General Assembly, its mission is to help Virginians with low and moderate income levels attain quality, affordable housing whether through rental programs or home ownership. VHDA strives to overcome barriers to homeownership, as well as to offer easily accessible products, programs and services. VHDA has developed several loan programs designed to meet the needs of low-and moderate-income consumers.
The Virginia Housing Development Authority is self-supporting and does not use tax dollars to fund its lending programs. The Authority sells bonds to the private sector in order to support its lending programs. From its own operating funds, VHDA finances the Virginia Housing Fund, which makes loans to homeownership and rental programs that serve Virginians who cannot be served by its traditional bond-funded programs.
The Virginia Housing Development Authority is a quasi-government agency, and as such, is subject to certain supervisory powers of the governor and the General Assembly. VHDA is required to submit annual reports of its operating and financial status, which are subject to review by the Auditor of Public Accounts. VHDA’s Board of Commissioners is composed of 11 members, all of whom are appointed by the governor. Eight members are direct appointees, including a Housing Choice Voucher Program representative. Day-to-day management is left to the executive director. In 1999, Susan F. Dewey became the executive director of VHDA.
Scope and Content
Director's correspondence and subject files include correspondence, board meeting materials, memoranda, reports, financial records, and legislative files.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Series I. Correspondence and subject files
Contents List
- Administrative Services Oversight, 1976 (Box 2)
- Bank Line of Credit: M-F Bond Anticipation Notes, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, 1977 April-June (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1977 July-August (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1977 September-October (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1977 November-December (Box 4)
- Correspondence - Incoming, 1980 January-March. (Box 1)
- Correspondence - Incoming, 1980 April-June. (Box 1)
- Correspondence - Incoming, 1980 July-September. (Box 1)
- Correspondence - Incoming, 1980 October-December. (Box 1)
- Correspondence - Miscellaneous (incoming and outgoing), 1980 (Box 1)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1973 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1974 (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1975 January-June (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1975 July-December (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1976 January-June (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1976 July-September (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1976 September-December (Box 3)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1980 January-March (Box 1)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1980 April-June (Box 1)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1980 July-August (Box 1)
- Correspondence - Outgoing, 1980 September-December (Box 1)
- Correspondence - State Legislators, 1980 (Box 1)
- Correspondence - U.S. Legislators, 1980 (Box 1)
- Economist Oversight, 1975 (Box 2)
- Finance Division Oversight, 1976 (Box 2)
- General Assembly, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- General Assembly, 1978 (Box 2)
- General Assembly, 1979-1980 (Box 2)
- Homestead meeting/Kenneth G. Hance - materials from development, 1976 (Box 2)
- Homestead, 1980 (Box 2)
- Housing Management Division Oversight, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
- Imperial Building, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
- Legal Divsion Oversight, 1975 (Box 2)
- Management Information Systems, 1976 (Box 2)
- Memoranda - Executive Division, 1976-1978 (Box 4)
- Memoranda - Executive Division, 1977 (Box 4)
- Memoranda - Ludwell F. Lee Jr., 1977-1978 (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
- Multi-Family Purchase Bonds - 1973 Series A, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
- Personnel, 1974-1977 (Box 2)
- Program Officer Oversight, 1975 (Box 2)
- Public Information Oversight, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
- Senate Joint Resolution 96, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
- Single Family Bonds - 1974 Series A, 1974 (Box 2)
- Virginia Housing Development Authority Commissioner and Staff workshop, 1980 (Box 2)
- Virginia Housing Study Commission, 1977 (Box 2)
- Virginia Housing Study Commission, 1978 (Box 2)
- Virginia Housing Study Commission - Charlottesville meeting, 1977 (Box 2)
- Virginia Housing Study Commission - Hearings and workshop, 1976 (Box 2)
- Virginia Housing Study Commission - House Resolution 35, 1979 (Box 2)
- Virginia Housing Study Commission - Organizational meeting, 1980 June 16 (Box 2)